<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>s p a c e</title>
    <link>https://henryhe.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on s p a c e</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>🌊 Henry He 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://henryhe.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
          <title>We Can Hack Pain — But Should We?</title>
          <link>https://henryhe.me/posts/hack/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://henryhe.me/posts/hack/</guid>
          <description>The Opioid Crisis, Soylent, and Retaining Humanity  Red opium poppy plants. Photo by Marten Bjork on Unsplash
I learned recently that Americans are the highest opioid users per capita in the world. That was no surprise. However, this next fact made me stop and think: there is no evidence that Americans experience any more pain than people from other countries.
A 2019 Lancet study found that the use of opioid analgesics (painkillers) in the USA far exceeds its use in other nations.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Knowing Your Limits is Strength, Not Weakness</title>
          <link>https://henryhe.me/posts/limits/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://henryhe.me/posts/limits/</guid>
          <description>Humility in medicine and in life  Photo by Jörg Angeli on Unsplash
The Hippocratic Oath is an oath of ethics traditionally taken by final year medical students as they graduate and become new physicians. In the modern version of the oath, new doctors are reminded of the importance of humility, and are encouraged to “not be ashamed to say ‘I know not,’ nor to call on colleagues when the skills of another are needed for a patient’s recovery.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Compassion vs. Burnout</title>
          <link>https://henryhe.me/posts/compassion/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://henryhe.me/posts/compassion/</guid>
          <description>A reminder of the limits of medicine  Clinician burnout is a huge problem in medicine, and can lead to lower patient care quality, higher medical error risk, physician alcohol and drug abuse and addiction, and physician suicide (source). In Canada, 30% of residents and practicing physicians report experiencing burnout (emotional exhaustion and/or depersonalization) at least weekly. Just last week, an emergency physician working in the COVID-19 units in New York died by suicide — now we don’t know the precise circumstances around her death, but based on the New York Times article, I think it is fair to say that stress from work likely played a role.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>The Dollar Value of a Human Life</title>
          <link>https://henryhe.me/posts/econ/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://henryhe.me/posts/econ/</guid>
          <description>Spoiler…it’s $10 million USD.  I heard a fascinating podcast episode from Planet Money titled “Lives Vs. The Economy” recently, and it blew my mind.
It addressed the question that has been asked more and more recently in the public discourse: “is it ever worth it to shut down the economy to save lives?”, or in other words, “Why can’t we open back up? I need to go back to work!</description>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Advice for students applying to medical school</title>
          <link>https://henryhe.me/posts/advice/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://henryhe.me/posts/advice/</guid>
          <description>Part of my story and what I learned from the process  I am a current second year medical student studying in Canada. Over the past couple years, I have had the pleasure to be able to give some advice and mentorship to friends in lower years. I personally reached out to many upper-year students for help when I was applying, so I am more than happy to give back.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>What if I told you that you could be your own ‘anxiety pill’?</title>
          <link>https://henryhe.me/posts/anxiety/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://henryhe.me/posts/anxiety/</guid>
          <description>Self-management of anxiety in a stressful world  Disclaimer: I am not a physician and this is not medical advice. It is just what I learned from a recent (virtual) psychiatry lecture. Please contact your family physician if you need medical care, this includes anything to do with mental illness.
Photo by Aliaksei Lepik on Unsplash
We had a lecture recently from Dr. Jon Davine, a dual psychiatry and family medicine trained physician.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>COVID-19 and Climate Change</title>
          <link>https://henryhe.me/posts/covid-19-and-climate-change/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://henryhe.me/posts/covid-19-and-climate-change/</guid>
          <description>Estimated reading time: 10 minutes… but there are pretty pictures!
I attended an online webinar the other day organized by the Canadian Association of Physicians for the Environment (CAPE). The session was titled “COVID-19 and climate change - Where do we go from here?” and consisted of a panel of speakers, including physicians and other board members of the organization. I was interested because I had heard something about carbon emissions dropping ever since people have been staying home and the economy had been slowing down.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>7 Tips for Starting Med School</title>
          <link>https://henryhe.me/posts/7-tips-for-starting-med-school/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 02:41:35 -0400</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://henryhe.me/posts/7-tips-for-starting-med-school/</guid>
          <description>&amp;hellip;#7 changed my LIFE!! Lol
Starting med school has been simultaneously the most exciting and the most overwhelming time of my life. It’s only been a month, and I already feel a lot of the responsibilities of “being a doctor”. Like Shakespeare wrote in Twelfth Night, it’s kind of been thrust upon me, all of a sudden. Starting the Problem Based Learning (PBL) model here at Mac was a little analogous to being thrown into the deep end, where at least before there were familiar creatures like marked exams and projects—have now been replaced by a void of vague tutorial objectives, optional anatomy labs, and “professional competency”.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>about</title>
          <link>https://henryhe.me/about/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://henryhe.me/about/</guid>
          <description>Hello internet wanderer! The idea of a static blog was inspired by my good friend Edward (edho.me) and serves as a space for my thoughts and reflections. I started it in order to write more, because I like writing and it helps me process life a bit better. Hopefully it is inspiring or interesting to you as well.
I am a second year medical student in Canada, so many of the posts will probably be medicine-related.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>music</title>
          <link>https://henryhe.me/music/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://henryhe.me/music/</guid>
          <description>So I like making music. I play piano, electric guitar, and sing, and I make my own beats too. I don&amp;rsquo;t have the greatest voice nor the greatest musical talent, but I love making covers of my favourite songs, because it&amp;rsquo;s a chance to experience them on a deeper level. Some of my biggest influences are Daniel Caesar, Rex Orange County, John Mayer, Still Woozy, Radiohead, and the Foo Fighters, in no particular order.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>PedsVitals 🧸❤️</title>
          <link>https://henryhe.me/pedsvitals/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          
          <guid>https://henryhe.me/pedsvitals/</guid>
          <description>The Story I&amp;rsquo;m Henry, a medical student in Hamilton, Ontario, and I&amp;rsquo;m currently about a third of the way through clerkship. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a little intimidated by pediatrics because it feels like kids are an entirely different species (like little aliens 👽). They are affected by different diseases, require different medication dosages, and their vitals are completely different compared to adults. Developmental milestones were also extremely hard for me to remember just because of how many milestones and categories there were.</description>
        </item>
        
  </channel>
</rss>
