<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>advice on s p a c e</title>
    <link>https://henryhe.me/tags/advice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in advice on s p a c e</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>🌊 Henry He 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://henryhe.me/tags/advice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowing Your Limits is Strength, Not Weakness</title>
      <link>https://henryhe.me/posts/limits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://henryhe.me/posts/limits/</guid>
      <description>Humility in medicine and in life  Photo by Jörg Angeli on Unsplash
The Hippocratic Oath is an oath of ethics traditionally taken by final year medical students as they graduate and become new physicians. In the modern version of the oath, new doctors are reminded of the importance of humility, and are encouraged to “not be ashamed to say ‘I know not,’ nor to call on colleagues when the skills of another are needed for a patient’s recovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compassion vs. Burnout</title>
      <link>https://henryhe.me/posts/compassion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://henryhe.me/posts/compassion/</guid>
      <description>A reminder of the limits of medicine  Clinician burnout is a huge problem in medicine, and can lead to lower patient care quality, higher medical error risk, physician alcohol and drug abuse and addiction, and physician suicide (source). In Canada, 30% of residents and practicing physicians report experiencing burnout (emotional exhaustion and/or depersonalization) at least weekly. Just last week, an emergency physician working in the COVID-19 units in New York died by suicide — now we don’t know the precise circumstances around her death, but based on the New York Times article, I think it is fair to say that stress from work likely played a role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice for students applying to medical school</title>
      <link>https://henryhe.me/posts/advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://henryhe.me/posts/advice/</guid>
      <description>Part of my story and what I learned from the process  I am a current second year medical student studying in Canada. Over the past couple years, I have had the pleasure to be able to give some advice and mentorship to friends in lower years. I personally reached out to many upper-year students for help when I was applying, so I am more than happy to give back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Tips for Starting Med School</title>
      <link>https://henryhe.me/posts/7-tips-for-starting-med-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 02:41:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://henryhe.me/posts/7-tips-for-starting-med-school/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip;#7 changed my LIFE!! Lol
Starting med school has been simultaneously the most exciting and the most overwhelming time of my life. It’s only been a month, and I already feel a lot of the responsibilities of “being a doctor”. Like Shakespeare wrote in Twelfth Night, it’s kind of been thrust upon me, all of a sudden. Starting the Problem Based Learning (PBL) model here at Mac was a little analogous to being thrown into the deep end, where at least before there were familiar creatures like marked exams and projects—have now been replaced by a void of vague tutorial objectives, optional anatomy labs, and “professional competency”.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>